Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end developer

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com | www.cathrinwill.com

Profile

I'm an experienced Front-end Developer having worked at a variety of digital and marketing agencies for over 5 years. With strong skills in writing HTML, CSS using Sass and javaScript using jQuery.

I'm passionate about continually improving the workflow using task runners such as Grunt, gulp and npm scripts.

I'm especially eager to make code more modular, maintainable and semantic as web standards progress, paying extra attention to decreasing load times and making sites more accessible and user friendly.

Skills Summary

Core Skills

- HTML
- CSS (Sass / SCSS / LESS)
- JavaScript / jQuery
- Grunt / Gulp / npm scripts
- Responsive web development
- Progressive enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Usability & UX considerations
- Cross browser compatibility
- Version control (Git / BitBucket)
- Adobe Suite (Illustrator & Photoshop)

Professional Experience

Front end Developer at Purple Agency

March 2013 – Present

- Building front-end responsive templates based on supplied designs using HTML, SCSS and grunt.
- Cross browser and A/B testing.
- · Building and setting up responsive email campaigns.
- Keeping clean and maintainable code.
- Staying up to date with web trends and new technologies.
- · Ensuring websites are accessibility friendly.
- Using semantic code, meta/micro data, and google analytics, to ensure SEO for sites.
- Using a combination of git, bitbucket, SourceTree and SVN for version control.

Front end Developer at Webexpectations

September 2012 – March 2013

• Building the front end from Photoshop/Illustrator templates, and creating standalone pages for multivariate testing.

Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end developer

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com | www.cathrinwill.com

- Experience gained from working with a variety of CMS'.
- Working with development processes including git for version control.
- Experience with responsive web development and mobile / retina display optimisation.
- Built HTML Emails and HTML email signatures.

Junior Web Developer at SuperReal GmbH, Germany April 2007 – October 2007

Work experience in Hamburg learning how to make websites, working with graphic designers and using Photoshop and Integrating front-end code with code written by backend developers. Taking extra care to make websites identical across browsers including such challenges as IE6/7 and the box model bug.

Education

Web Development with Business BSc (Hons), Kingston University 2009 – 2012

- Learned the foundations to several previously self taught languages.
- Got a basic understanding of a variety of web languages.
- Worked in a lot of groups often taking on the role of organiser within it.
- Always ensured to hand in every coursework before the deadline.
- Helped peers with their work, and vice versa learned a lot from them.
- Thoroughly enjoyed working on the Single Semester Final Year Project, the end result which can be viewed on http://pixxy.cathrinwill.com/

Computer Information Systems and Mathematics Foundation 2008 – 2009 Kingston College, Kingston upon Thames

Interests

Apart from keeping up to date with anything surrounding web development by subscribing to a number of blogs, I greatly enjoy sunshine, hiking, science and reading.

Languages

English (Bilingual proficiency)
German (Bilingual proficiency)

References

Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end developer

Woking, Surrey

ann@cathrinwill.com | www.cathrinwill.com

Available on request.